Kelly Flynn Applications Engineer

Medford, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Kelly-Flynn/b975ec5c8e9d2dff

Environmental engineer, scientist and biologist who has worked extensively in the fields of environmental and water resources. Strong technical and analytical skills, including: field and laboratory work, data analysis and maintenance, writing, environmental regulations, process management, continuous improvement implementation, bid strategy and project execution. Personal strengths include: hard worker, self-starter, dedicated, organized, detail oriented, analytical, creative, problem solver, adaptive, personable, leadership, team player, fidelity

WORK EXPERIENCE

Applications Engineer

Siemens Industry, Inc - Vineland, NJ - March 2009 to October 2012

Designed chemical disinfection applications and water/wastewater treatment systems for municipal and industrial projects, both domestically and internationally

- Analyzed water quality reports; ensured compliance with environmental standards and regulations
- Created and reviewed plans, specifications, and manuals; generated proposals and accurate pricing for bids
- Technical resource: provided presentations and Q&A sessions; trained customers and fellow employees
- Involved in all project stages: applications, project management and execution, including factory testing
- · Attended corporate meetings and implemented policies; designed a risk management system
- Departmental CIP Workgroup Leader; Departmental ISO Team Leader

Graduate Research Assistant

Villanova University - June 2007 to December 2008

Researched and managed a constructed stormwater wetland: took field samples and ran laboratory water quality tests; designed a plot study to compare the pollutant removal capabilities of different plants

 Wrote a thesis on the pollutant removal efficiency and water quality of a mature constructed stormwater wetland during times of baseflow and storm events

Research Assistant

Villanova University - August 2006 to April 2007

Used microbial source tracking techniques to develop Fatty Acid Methyl Ester profiles of E. coli and enterococci in order to track sources of fecal pollution in various water bodies throughout southeastern PA

Operations Manager

Response Force, Inc - Marlton, NJ - August 2005 to January 2007

Implemented customer resource management systems

Led market research projects

Intern

Alaska Wilderness League - Capitol Hill, WA - January 2004 to May 2004

Assisted in organizing events and contacting senators, congressman, organizations and media

• Gained experience in environmental regulations and conservation

International Mission on Medicine - May 2003 to June 2003

Attended medical conferences and environmental lectures while accumulating research experience in sanctuaries, the rainforest, Aboriginal parks, and the Great Barrier Reef

EDUCATION

Master's in Water Resources and Environmental Engineering

Villanova University - Villanova, PA April 2000

B.S. in Biology, Theology

Georgetown University - Washington, DC April 2000

Bishop Eustace Preparatory School - Pennsauken, NJ

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills

Computer

AutoCAD, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook), Acrobat, SAP, Dodge, Reed Connect, CRM, McAfee, Ad-Aware, Movie Maker, Photosmart

Laboratory/Field Work

Water quality (sampling, testing and analysis), Sigma flow meters and water samplers, Data Transfer Units, Pressure Transducers, Sondes

Hobbies/Interests

Accomplished pianist, guitar, banjo and flute player, avid reader, animal and nature lover, sports, outdoor activities

Charity Work: Special Olympics (Philadelphia Management Team and Coach), Big Brothers Big Sisters, ASPCA, American Red Cross, American Cancer Society

LinkedIn

http://www.linkedin.com/in/kellyccflynn